For linear regression, we had
对于线性回归的求解 我们之前
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
previously worked out two learning
推导了两种学习算法
algorithms, one based on
一种基于梯度下降
gradient descent and one based on the normal equation.
一种基于正规方程
In this video we will take
在这段视频中 我们将继续学习
those two algorithms and generalize
这两个算法 并把它们推广
them to the case of regularized
到正则化线性回归中去
linear regression. Here's the
这是我们上节课推导出的
optimization objective, that we
正则化线性回归的
came up with last time for regularized linear regression.
优化目标
This first part is our
前面的第一部分是
usual, objective for linear regression,
一般线性回归的目标函数
and we now have this additional
而现在我们有这个额外的
regularization term, where londer
正则化项 其中 λ
is our regularization parameter, and
是正则化参数
we like to find parameters theta,
我们想找到参数 θ
that minimizes this cost function,
能最小化代价函数
this regularized cost function, J of theta.
即这个正则化代价函??数 J(θ)
Previously, we were using
之前 我们使用
gradient descent for the original
梯度下降求解原来
cost function, without the regularization
没有正则项的代价函数
term, and we had
我们用
the following algorithm for regular
下面的算法求解常规的
linear regression, without regularization.
没有正则项的线性回归
We will repeatedly update the
我们会如此反复更新
parameters theta J as follows
参数 θj
for J equals 1,2 up
其中 j=0, 1, 2...n
through n. Let me
让我
take this and just write
照这个把
the case for theta zero separately.
j=0 即 θ0 的情况单独写出来
So, you know, I'm just gonna
我只是把
write the update for theta
θ0 的更新
zero separately, then for
分离出来
the update for the parameters
剩下的这些参数θ1, θ2 到θn的更新
1, 2, 3, and so on up
作为另一部分
to n. So, I haven't changed anything yet, right?
所以 这样做其实没有什么变化 对吧？
This is just writing the update
这只是把 θ0 的更新
for theta zero separately from the
updates from theta 1, theta
和 θ1 θ2 到 θn 的更新分离开来
2, theta 3, up to theta n. And
the reason I want to do this
我这样做的原因是
is you may remember
你可能还记得
that for our regularized linear regression,
对于正则化的线性回归
we penalize the parameters theta
我们惩罚参数θ1
1, theta 2, and so
θ2...一直到
on up to theta n, but we don't penalize theta zero.
θn  但是我们不惩罚θ0
So when we modify this
所以 当我们修改这个
algorithm for regularized
正则化线性回归的算法时
linear regression, we're going to
我们将对
end up treating theta zero slightly differently.
θ0 的方式将有所不同
Concretely, if we
具体地说 如果我们
want to take this algorithm and
要对这个算法进行
modify it to use the
修改 并用它
regularized objective, all we
求解正则化的目标函数 我们
need to do is take this
需要做的是
term at the bottom and modify as follows.
把下边的这一项做如下的修改
We're gonna take this term and add
我们要在这一项上添加一项:
minus londer M,
λ 除以 m
times theta J. And
再乘以 θj
if you implement this, then you
如果这样做的话 那么你就有了
have gradient descent for trying
用于最小化
to minimize the regularized cost
正则化代价函数 J(θ)
function J of F theta, and concretely,
的梯度下降算法
I'm not gonna do the
我不打算用
calculus to prove it, but
微积分来证明这一点
concretely if you look
但如果你看这一项
at this term, this term that's written is square brackets.
方括号里的这一项
If you know calculus, it's possible
如果你知道微积分
to prove that that term is
应该不难证明它是
the partial derivative, with respect of
J(θ) 对 θj 的偏导数
J of theta, using the new
这里的 J(θ) 是用的新定义的形式
definition of J of theta
它的定义中
with the regularization term.
包含正则化项
And somebody on this
而另一项
term up on top,
上面的这一项
which I guess I am
我用青色的方框
drawing the salient box
圈出来的这一项
that's still the partial derivative
这也一个是偏导数
respect of theta zero for J of theta.
是 J(θ)对 θ0 的偏导数
If you look at the update for
如果你仔细看 θj 的更新
theta J, it's possible to
你会发现一些
show's something pretty interesting, concretely
有趣的东西 具体来说
theta J gets updated as
θj 的每次更新
theta J, minus alpha times,
都是 θj 自己减去 α 乘以原来的无正则项
and then you have this other term
然后还有这另外的一项
here that depends on theta J
这一项的大小也取决于 θj
. So if you
所以 如果你
group all the terms together
把所有这些
that depending on theta J. We
取决于 θj 的合在一起的话
can show that this update can
可以证明 这个更新
be written equivalently as
可以等价地写为
follows and all I did
如下的形式
was have, you know, theta J
具体来讲 上面的 θj
here is theta J times
对应下面的 θj 乘以括号里的1
1 and this term is
而这一项是
londer over M. There's also an alpha
λ 除以 m 还有一个α
here, so you end up
把它们合在一起 所以你最终得到
with alpha londer over
α 乘以 λ 再除以 m
m, multiply them to
然后合在一起 乘以 θj
theta J and this term here, one minus
而这一项
alpha times londer M, is
1 减去 α 乘以 λ 除以 m
a pretty interesting term, it has a pretty interesting effect.
这一项很有意思
Concretely, this term one
具体来说 这一项
minus alpha times londer over
1 减去 α 乘以 λ 除以 m
M, is going to be
这一项的值
a number that's, you know, usually a number
通常是一个具体的实数
that's a loop and less than 1,
而且小于1
right? Because of
对吧？由于
alpha times londer over M is
α 乘以 λ 除以 m
going to be positive and usually, if you're learning rate is small and M is large.
通常情况下是正的 如果你的学习速率小 而 m 很大的话
That's usually pretty small.
(1 - αλ/m) 这一项通常是很小的
So this term here, it's going
所以这里的一项
to be a number, it's usually, you know, a little bit less than one.
一般来说将是一个比1小一点点的值
So think of it as
所以我们可以把它想成
a number like 0.99, let's say
一个像0.99一样的数字
and so, the effect of our
所以
updates of theta J is we're
对 θj 更新的结果
going to say that theta J
我们可以看作是
gets replaced by thetata J times 0.99.
被替换为 θj 的0.99倍
Alright so theta J
也就是 θj
times 0.99 has the effect of
乘以0.99
shrinking theta J a little bit towards 0.
把 θj 向 0 压缩了一点点
So this makes theta J a bit smaller.
所以这使得 θj 小了一点
More formally, this you know, this
更正式地说
square norm of theta J
θj 的平方范数
is smaller and then
更小了
after that the second
另外 这一项后边的第二项
term here, that's actually
这实际上
exactly the same as the
与我们原来的
original gradient descent updated that we had.
梯度下降更新完全一样
Before we added all this regularization stuff.
跟我们加入了正则项之前一样
So, hopefully this gradient
好的 现在你应该对这个
descent, hopefully this update makes
梯度下降的更新没有疑问了
sense, when we're using regularized linear
当我们使用正则化线性回归时
regression what we're doing is on
我们需要做的就是
every regularization were multiplying data
在每一个被正规化的参数 θj 上
J by a number that
乘以了一个
is a little bit less than one, so
比1小一点点的数字
we're shrinking the parameter a
也就是把参数压缩了一点
little bit, and then we're
然后
performing a, you know, similar update as before.
我们执行跟以前一样的更新
Of course that's just the
当然 这仅仅是
intuition behind what this particular update is doing.
从直观上认识 这个更新在做什么
Mathematically, what it's doing
从数学上讲
is exactly gradient descent on
它就是带有正则化项的 J(θ)
the cost function J of theta
的梯度下降算法
that we defined on the previous
我们在之前的幻灯片
slide that uses the regularization term.
给出了定义
Gradient descent was just
梯度下降只是
one our two algorithms for
我们拟合线性回归模型的两种算法
fitting a linear regression model.
的其中一个
The second algorithm was the
第二种算法是
one based on the normal
使用正规方程
equation where, what we
我们的做法
did was we created the
是建立这个
design matrix "x" where each
设计矩阵 X 其中每一行
row corresponded to a separate training example.
对应于一个单独的训练样本
And we created a vector
然后创建了一个向量 y
Y, so this is
向量 y 是一个
a vector that is an
m 维的向量
M dimensional vector and that
contain the labels from a training set.
包含了所有训练集里的标签
So whereas X is an
所以 X 是一个
M by N plus 1 dimensional matrix.
m × (n+1) 维矩阵
Y is an M dimensional
y 是一个 m 维向量
vector and in order
to minimize the cost
为了最小化代价函数 J
function change we found
我们发现
that of one way
一个办法就是
to do is to set
theta to be equal to this.
让 θ 等于这个式子
We have X transpose X,
即 X 的转置乘以 X 再对结果取逆
inverse X transpose Y.
再乘以 X 的转置乘以Y
I am leaving room here, to fill
我在这里留点空间
in stuff of course. And what this
等下再填满
value for theta does, is
这个 θ 的值
this minimizes the cost
其实就是最小化
function J of theta when
代价函数 J(θ) 的θ值
we were not using regularization. Now
这时的代价函数J(θ)没有正则项
that we are using regularization, if
现在如果我们用了是正则化
you were to derive what the
我们想要得到最小值
minimum is, and just to
give you a sense of how to
我们来看看应该怎么得到
derive the minimum, the way
you derive it is you know,
推导的方法是
take partial derivatives in respect
取 J 关于各个参数的偏导数
to each parameter, set this
并令它们
to zero, and then do
等于0 然后做些
a bunch of math, and you can
数学推导 你可以
then show that is a formula
得到这样的一个式子
like this that minimizes the cost function.
它使得代价函数最小
And concretely, if you
具体的说 如果你
are using regularization then this
使用正则化
formula changes as follows. Inside this
那么公式要做如下改变
parenthesis, you end up with a matrix like this.
括号里结尾添这样一个矩阵
Zero, one, one, one
0 1 1 1 等等
and so on, one until the bottom.
直到最后一行
So this thing over here is
所以这个东西在这里是
a matrix, who's upper leftmost entry is zero.
一个矩阵 它的左上角的元素是0
There's ones on the diagonals and
其余对角线元素都是1
then the zeros everywhere else on this matrix.
剩下的元素也都是 0
Because I am drawing this a little bit sloppy.
我画的比较随意
But as a concrete
可以举一个例子
example if N equals 2,
如果 n 等于2
then this matrix
那么这个矩阵
is going to be a three by three matrix.
将是一个3 × 3 矩阵
More generally, this matrix is
更一般地情况 该矩阵是
a N plus one
一个 (n+1) × (n+1) 维的矩阵
by N plus one dimensional matrix.
So then N equals two then that
因此 n 等于2时
matrix becomes something that looks like this.
矩阵看起来会像这样
Zero, and then ones
左上角是0
on the diagonals, and then
然后其他对角线上是1
zeros on the rest of the diagonals.
其余部分都是0
And once again, you know, I'm not going to those this derivation.
同样地 我不打算对这些作数学推导
Which is frankly somewhat long and involved.
坦白说这有点费时耗力
But it is possible to prove
但可以证明
that if you are
如果你采用新定义的 J(θ)
using the new definition of
J of theta, with the regularization objective.
包含正则项的目标函数
Then this new formula for
那么这个计算 θ 的式子
theta is the one
能使你的 J(θ)
that will give you the global minimum of J of theta.
达到全局最小值
So finally, I want to
所以最后
just quickly describe the issue of non-invertibility.
我想快速地谈一下不可逆性的问题
This is relatively advanced material.
这部分是比较高阶的内容
So you should consider this as
所以这一部分还是作为选学
optional and feel free
你可以跳过去
to skip it or if you
或者你也可以听听
listen to it and you know, possibly it
如果听不懂的话
don't really make sense, don't worry about it either.
也没有关系
But earlier when I talked the normal equation method.
之前当我讲正规方程的时候
We also had an optional video
我们也有一段选学视频
on the non-invertability issue.
讲不可逆的问题
So this is another optional part,
所以这是另一个选学内容
that is sort of add on
可以作为上次视频的补充
earlier optional video on non-invertibility.
Now considering setting where M
现在考虑 m
the number of examples is less
即样本总数
than or equal to N the number features.
小与或等于特征数量 n
If you have fewer examples then
如果你的样本数量
features then this matrix
比特征数量小的话  那么这个矩阵
X transpose X will be
X 转置乘以 X 将是
non-invertible or singular, or
不可逆或奇异的(singluar)
the other term
或者用另一种说法是
for this is the matrix will
这个矩阵是
be degenerate and if
退化(degenerate)的
you implement this in Octave
如果你在 Octave 里运行它
anyway, and you use the
无论如何
P in function to take the psuedo inverse.
你用函数 pinv 取伪逆矩阵
It will kind of do the
这样计算
right thing that is not
理论上方法是正确的
clear that it will
但实际上
give you a very good hypothesis
你不会得到一个很好的假设
even though numerically the octave
尽管 Ocatve 会
P in function
用 pinv 函数
will give you a result that
给你一个数值解
kind of makes sense.
看起来还不错
But, if you were doing this in a different language.
但是 如果你是在一个不同的编程语言中
And if you were
如果在 Octave 中
taking just the regular inverse
你用 inv 来取常规逆
which an octave is denoted with the function INV.
We're trying to take the regular
也就是我们要对
inverse of X transpose X,
X 转置乘以 X 取常规逆
then in this setting you
然后在这样的情况下
find that X transpose X
你会发现 X 转置乘以 X
is singular, is non-invertible and
是奇异的 是不可逆的
if you're doing this in a different
即使你在不同的
programming language and using some
编程语言里计算 并使用一些
linear algebra library try to take the inverse of this matrix.
线性代数库 试图计算这个矩阵的逆矩阵
It just might not work because that
都是不可行的
matrix is non-invertible or singular.
因为这个矩阵是不可逆的或奇异的
Fortunately, regularization also takes
幸运的是 正规化也
care of this for us, and concretely, so
为我们解决了这个问题 具体地说
long as the regularization parameter is strictly greater than zero.
只要正则参数是严格大于0的
It is actually possible to
实际上 可以
prove that this matrix X
证明该矩阵 X 转置 乘以 X
transpose X plus parameter time, you know,s
加上 λ 乘以
this funny matrix here,
这里这个矩阵
is possible to prove that this
可以证明
matrix will not be
这个矩阵将不是奇异的
singular and that this matrix will be invertible.
即该矩阵将是可逆的
So using regularization also takes
因此 使用正则化还可以
care of any non-invertibility issues
照顾一些 X 转置乘以 X 不可逆的问题
of the X transpose X matrix as well.
So, you now know how to implement regularize linear regression.
好的 你现在知道了如何实现正则化线性回归
Using this, you'll be able
利用它 你就可以
to avoid overfitting, even
避免过度拟合
if you have lots of features in a relatively small training set.
即使你在一个相对较小的训练集里有很多特征
And this should let you get
这应该可以让你
linear regression to work much better for many problems.
在很多问题上更好地运用线性回归
In the next video, we'll take
在接下来的视频中 我们将
this regularization idea and apply it to logistic regression.
把这种正则化的想法应用到逻辑回归
So that you'll be able to
这样你就可以
get logistic impression to avoid
让逻辑回归也避免过度拟合
overfitting and perform much better as well.
并让它表现的更好